<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paper on HPCAT</title>
    <link>https://hpcat.github.io/categories/paper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paper on HPCAT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hpcat.github.io/categories/paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Hao Zheng for winning the second place in Engineering categorize at the GW Research Days</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/02/hao/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/02/hao/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Hao Zheng, PhD student at HPCAT lab, for winning the second place in the Engineering categorize at the GW Research Days. His contribution was on designing an energy-efficient scalable multicore architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Ke Wang for winning the AccelerateGW I-Crops site Grant</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/02/cory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/02/cory/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Ke Wang, PhD student at HPCAT lab, for winning the AccelerateGW I-Crops site grant award. With this award, Ke will be able to travel to conferences to present his research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Accepted Papers at DAC-2018 and IPDPS-2018</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/14/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/14/paper1/</guid>
      <description>The following papers have been accepted at DAC-2018 and IPDPS-2018.
Mark Clark, Avinash Kodi, Razvan Bunescu, and Ahmed Louri LEAD: Learning-enabled Energy-Aware Dynamic Voltage/Frequency Scaling in NoCs Accepted to appear in 55th Design Automation Conference (DAC-2018), San Fransisco, CA, June 24-28, 2018.
Avinash Kodi, Kyle Shifflet, Savas Kaya, Ahmed Louri and Soumyasanta Laha Scalable Power-Efficient Kilo-Core Photonic-Wireless NoC Architectures Accepted to appear in 32nd IEEE International Parallel and Distributed Processing Symposium (IPDPS-2018), Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, May 21-25, 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Louri and his Research Team have Published an IEEE International Symposium Conference Paper titled: “Extending the Power-Efficiency and Performance of Photonic Interconnects for Heterogeneous Multicores with Machine Learning”</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/12/paper3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/12/paper3/</guid>
      <description>Professor Ahmed Louri and his research team (S. V. Winkle, A. Kodi, R. Bunescu and A. Louri) have published a conference paper that explores machine learning to extend the power-efficieny and performance of photonic interconnects for heterogeneous multicores. The paper titled “Extending the Power-Efficiency and Performance of Photonic Interconnects for Heterogeneous Multicores with Machine Learning,” will appear in Proceedings of the 24th IEEE International Symposium on High-Performance Computer Architecture, Feb. 24-28, 2018, Vienna.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Louri and his Research Team have Published a USNC_USRI NAtional Radio Science Meeting Conference Paper titled: “Reconfigurable Intra-chip Antenna for Future Wireless Communications”</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/11/paper5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/11/paper5/</guid>
      <description>Professor Ahmed Louri and his research team (Y. Sharma, J. Wu, A. Kantemur, J. Tak, A. Kodi, S. Kaya and H. Xin) have published a conference paper that explores future wireless communications via reconfigurable intra-chip antenna. The paper titled “Reconfigurable Intra-Chip Antenna for Future Wireless Communications,” will appear in Proceedings of the 2018 USNC-USRI National Radio Science Meeting (NRSM), Jan. 4-7, 2018, Boulder, CO. NRSM is an open scientific meeting sponsored by the U.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>