<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paper on HPCAT</title>
    <link>https://hpcat.github.io/categories/paper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paper on HPCAT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hpcat.github.io/categories/paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Graduate students Ke Wang and Hao Zheng win awards at the George Washington Research Days Competition</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/02/haocory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/02/haocory/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Louri research students Hao Zheng and Ke Wang participated in competition Research Days hosted at The George Washington University. Both students presented their respective research topics: &amp;ldquo;Energy-efficient Scalable Multicore Architecture&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Machine Learning for High Performance, Energy-efficient and Reliable NoCs&amp;rdquo;. Hao placed 2nd in the Graduate Engineering category and Ke won the AccelerateGW I-Corps Site Grant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Louri and his Research Team submitted a paper titled: “LEAD: Learning-enabled Energy-Aware Dynamic Voltage/Frequency Scaling in NoCs” at the Design Automation Conference, which  was accepted</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/14/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/14/paper1/</guid>
      <description>Professor Ahmed Louri and his research team (M. Clark, A. Kodi, R. Bunescu and A. Louri) conference paper that explores learning-enabled, energy-aware dynamic voltage and frequency scaling in NOCs was accepted. The paper titled &amp;ldquo;LEAD: Learning-Enabled Energy-Aware Dynamic Voltage/Frequency Scaling in NoCs,&amp;rdquo; will appear in Proceedings of the 55th ACM/EDAC/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC), June 24-28, 2018, San Francisco, CA. DAC is the world&amp;rsquo;s premier EDA and semiconductor design conference and exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Louri and his Research Team submitted a paper titled: “Power-Efficient Kilo-Core Photonic-Wireless Hybrid NoCs” at the IEEE International Symposium Conference, which was accepted</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/13/paper2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/13/paper2/</guid>
      <description>Professor Ahmed Louri and his research team (A. Kodi, K. Shiflett, S. Kaya, S. Laha and A. Louri) conference paper that explores power-efficient, kilo-core, photonic-wireless, hybrid Network-on-Chips was accepted. The paper titled &amp;ldquo;Power-Efficient Kilo-Core Photonic-Wireless Hybrid NoCs,” will appear in Proceedings of the 32nd IEEE International Parallel and Distributed Processing Symposium (IPDPS), May 21-25, 2018, Vancouver, BC. IPDPS is an international forum for engineers and scientists from around the world to present their latest research findings in all aspects of parallel computation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Louri and his Research Team published a paper titled: “Extending the Power-Efficiency and Performance of Photonic Interconnects for Heterogeneous Multicores with Machine Learning” at the IEEE International Symposium Conference</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/12/paper3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/12/paper3/</guid>
      <description>Professor Ahmed Louri and his research team (S. V. Winkle, A. Kodi, R. Bunescu and A. Louri) have published a conference paper that explores machine learning to extend the power-efficieny and performance of photonic interconnects for heterogeneous multicores. The paper titled “Extending the Power-Efficiency and Performance of Photonic Interconnects for Heterogeneous Multicores with Machine Learning,” will appear in Proceedings of the 24th IEEE International Symposium on High-Performance Computer Architecture, Feb. 24-28, 2018, Vienna.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Louri and his Research Team published a paper titled: “Reconfigurable Intra-chip Antenna for Future Wireless Communications” at the USNC_USRI NAtional Radio Science Meeting Conference</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/11/paper5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/11/paper5/</guid>
      <description>Professor Ahmed Louri and his research team (Y. Sharma, J. Wu, A. Kantemur, J. Tak, A. Kodi, S. Kaya and H. Xin) have published a conference paper that explores future wireless communications via reconfigurable intra-chip antenna. The paper titled “Reconfigurable Intra-Chip Antenna for Future Wireless Communications,” will appear in Proceedings of the 2018 USNC-USRI National Radio Science Meeting (NRSM), Jan. 4-7, 2018, Boulder, CO. NRSM is an open scientific meeting sponsored by the U.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>