<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HPCAT</title>
    <link>https://hpcat.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HPCAT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hpcat.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Ahmed Louri received a National Science Foundation award for the project “Integrated Framework for System-Level Approximate Computing”</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/18/nsfaward/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/18/nsfaward/</guid>
      <description>The project is a three-year collaborative effort with Dr. Fabrizio Lombardi (Northeastern University). The total amount of funding is $487,000, and GW’s portion is $262,000. In this research, Dr. Louri and his team seek to investigate and improve the advances and unique advantages of approximate computing to develop systems in both hardware and software (algorithms) that are low-power, high performance, and error-configurable. The overarching goal of this proposal is to develop computing systems that are capable of adjusting performance by exploiting relationships between hardware and software for different applications such as cognitive processing, digital signal/image processing, big data, and scientific processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Ahmed Louri is serving as the general chair of the 25th International Symposium on High-Performance Computer Architecture (HPCA - 2019)</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/10/hpcachair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/10/hpcachair/</guid>
      <description>Prof. Ahmed Louri is serving as general chair for HPCA 2019 which will be held in Washington D.C.(http://hpca2019.seas.gwu.edu). Preparations are under way for the 25th anniversary of this premier conference on computer architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Hao Zheng for winning the second place in Engineering categorize at the GW Research Days</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/02/hao/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/02/hao/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Hao Zheng, PhD student at HPCAT lab, for winning the second place in the Engineering categorize at the GW Research Days. His contribution was on designing an energy-efficient scalable multicore architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Ke Wang for winning the AccelerateGW I-Crops site Grant</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/02/cory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/05/02/cory/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Ke Wang, PhD student at HPCAT lab, for winning the AccelerateGW I-Crops site grant award. With this award, Ke will be able to travel to conferences to present his research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Accepted Papers at DAC-2018 and IPDPS-2018</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/14/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/14/paper1/</guid>
      <description>The following papers have been accepted at DAC-2018 and IPDPS-2018.
Mark Clark, Avinash Kodi, Razvan Bunescu, and Ahmed Louri LEAD: Learning-enabled Energy-Aware Dynamic Voltage/Frequency Scaling in NoCs Accepted to appear in 55th Design Automation Conference (DAC-2018), San Fransisco, CA, June 24-28, 2018.
Avinash Kodi, Kyle Shifflet, Savas Kaya, Ahmed Louri and Soumyasanta Laha Scalable Power-Efficient Kilo-Core Photonic-Wireless NoC Architectures Accepted to appear in 32nd IEEE International Parallel and Distributed Processing Symposium (IPDPS-2018), Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, May 21-25, 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Louri and his Research Team have Published an IEEE International Symposium Conference Paper titled: “Extending the Power-Efficiency and Performance of Photonic Interconnects for Heterogeneous Multicores with Machine Learning”</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/12/paper3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/12/paper3/</guid>
      <description>Professor Ahmed Louri and his research team (S. V. Winkle, A. Kodi, R. Bunescu and A. Louri) have published a conference paper that explores machine learning to extend the power-efficieny and performance of photonic interconnects for heterogeneous multicores. The paper titled “Extending the Power-Efficiency and Performance of Photonic Interconnects for Heterogeneous Multicores with Machine Learning,” will appear in Proceedings of the 24th IEEE International Symposium on High-Performance Computer Architecture, Feb. 24-28, 2018, Vienna.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Louri and his Research Team have Published a USNC_USRI NAtional Radio Science Meeting Conference Paper titled: “Reconfigurable Intra-chip Antenna for Future Wireless Communications”</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/11/paper5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/11/paper5/</guid>
      <description>Professor Ahmed Louri and his research team (Y. Sharma, J. Wu, A. Kantemur, J. Tak, A. Kodi, S. Kaya and H. Xin) have published a conference paper that explores future wireless communications via reconfigurable intra-chip antenna. The paper titled “Reconfigurable Intra-Chip Antenna for Future Wireless Communications,” will appear in Proceedings of the 2018 USNC-USRI National Radio Science Meeting (NRSM), Jan. 4-7, 2018, Boulder, CO. NRSM is an open scientific meeting sponsored by the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Louri and his Research Team have published an IEEE Transactions Article titled: “Sustainability in Network-on-Chips by Exploring Heterogeneity in Emerging Technologies”</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/09/article1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/blog/2018/03/09/article1/</guid>
      <description>Professor Ahmed Louri and his research team (A. Sikder, A. Kodi, S. Kaya, D. Carbaugh, S. Laha, A. Louri, H. Xin and J. Wu) have published a journal article that explores heterogeneity in emerging technologies in order to enhance sustainability of Network-on-Chips. The paper titled “Sustainability in Network-on-Chips by Exploring Heterogeneity in Emerging Technologies” will appear in IEEE Transactions on Sustainable Computing in 2018. This research was sponsored by the National Science Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Director</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/professor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 21:32:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/professor/</guid>
      <description>-- Ahmed Louri IEEE Fellow David and Marilyn Karlgaard Endowed Chair Professor of ECE Director, High Performance Computing Architectures and Technologies Lab (HPCAT) Associate Editor, IEEE Transactions on Emerging Topics in Computing Associate Editor, IEEE Transactions on Sustainable Computing 
-- Dr. Ahmed Louri is the David and Marilyn Karlgaard Endowed Chair Professor of Electrical and Computer Engineering at the George Washington University, which he joined in August 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Positions</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/position/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:50:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/position/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the HPCAT Lab! Students in the HPCAT Lab work on designing, developing and validating novel power-efficient, performance-adaptive, fault-tolerant and self-healing networks for High-Performance Computing (HPC) systems and multicore architectures. Students gain a well-rounded experience in computer and communication systems design through solid theoritical studies, modeling and simulation experiments, performance evaluation and physical implementation. A variety of modeling and simulation tools as well as equipments are available for use in the Lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the HPCAT Lab! Students in the HPCAT Lab work on designing, developing and validating novel power-efficient, performance-adaptive, fault-tolerant and self-healing networks for High-Performance Computing (HPC) systems and multicore architectures. Students gain a well-rounded experience in computer and communication systems design through solid theoritical studies, modeling and simulation experiments, performance evaluation and physical implementation. A variety of modeling and simulation tools as well as equipments are available for use in the Lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/hpcat_members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/hpcat_members/</guid>
      <description>Post-Doctorate | Graduate Students | Undergraduate Students Select a category</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/members/</guid>
      <description>  Post-Doctorate | Graduate Students | Undergraduate Students 
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members : Graduate Students</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/grad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/grad/</guid>
      <description>Post-Doctorate | Graduate Students | Undergraduate Students Hao Zheng Hao Zheng is working on building a power-efficient Network-on-Chips (NoCs). His primary research interests are energy and performance optimization of the multi-core system. 

Priyankar Roychowdhury Priyankar is investigating how to implement emerging optical technologies in interconnects of data centers as well as in main-stream computer architecture to achieve better performance. 
Ke Wang Ke’s research area lies on machine learning and NoCs design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members : Post-Doctorate</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/pgrad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/pgrad/</guid>
      <description>Post-Doctorate | Graduate Students | Undergraduate Students  
Md Farhadur Reza Md Farhadur Reza is a Post-Doctoral Scientist in the High Performance Computing Architectures and Technologies Laboratory (HPCAT) at the George Washington University. He received PhD and MS in computer science from the Center for Advanced Computer Studies (CACS) at the University of Louisiana at Lafayette in 2017 and 2014, respectively. His research interests include high-performance many-core architecture, energy efficient networks-on-chip, resource management and optimization, and machine learning techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members : Undergreaduate Students</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/under/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/under/</guid>
      <description>Post-Doctorate | Graduate Students | Undergraduate Students   Sebastian Foubert Sebastian is a Computer Engineering major graduating in 2019. In 2018, he will be at NVIDIA, writing systems code for self-driving cars. In 2017 he worked in the Platform Engineering Group at Intel. His interests are systems and computer architecture. 
Parmvir Chahal Parmvir assists the laboratory in researching Network-on-Chips (NoCs) via tools such as WinMIPS. In addition, he aids the Graduate Research Assistants by maintaining a database of the sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEWS</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/underc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/underc/</guid>
      <description>UNDER CONSTRUCTION</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications : Book Chapters</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/bookchapters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/bookchapters/</guid>
      <description>Journal Papers | Conference Papers | Book Chapters    //p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { content: &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; ; margin: 2em; display: block; font-size: 5px; }  
 R. Morris, A. K. Kodi and A. Louri, &amp;ldquo;Scalable Two-dimensional optical interconnects for data centers,&amp;rdquo; in Optical Interconnects for Data Centers, 1st ed., vol. , T. Tekin, N. Pleros, R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications : Conference Papers</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/conferences/</guid>
      <description>Journal Papers | Conference Papers | Book Chapters    //p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { content: &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; ; margin: 2em; display: block; font-size: 5px; }  
 Y. Chen, M.F. Reza and A. Louri, &amp;ldquo;DEC-NoC: An Approximate Framework based on Dynamic Error Control with Applications to Energy-efficient NoCs,&amp;rdquo; to appear in Proceedings of the 36th IEEE International Conference on Computer Design (ICCD), Orlando, FL, October 7-10, 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications : Journal Papers</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/journals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/journals/</guid>
      <description>Journal Papers | Conference Papers | Book Chapters    //p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { content: &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; ; margin: 2em; display: block; font-size: 5px; }  
 Q. Fettes, M. Clark, R. Bunescu, A. Karanth, and A. Louri, &amp;ldquo;Dynamic Voltage and Frequency Scaling in NoCs with Supervised and Reinforcement Learning Techniques,&amp;rdquo; to appear in IEEE Transactions on Computers (TC), 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/design_reconfig/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/design_reconfig/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Design of Reconfigurable and Scalable Optical Interconnection Networks for Balanced Parallel Computing Systems   Project Description 
The dramatic scaling and improvements in complementary metal-oxide semiconductor (CMOS) technology, coupled with innovations in computer architecture, have created an information technology society and a national economy very much dependent on a steady exponential growth in computing power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/emerging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/emerging/</guid>
      <description>Emerging Interconnects Technologies for Network-on-Chips   Current Researchers: TBD; 
There is a shift from multi-core to many-core architectures containing hundreds to a thousand cores on a single chip. However, traditional on-chip metallic interconnects require excessive power as technology keeps scaling and will not be able to provide communication support for manycore architectures. Moreover, fundamental signaling limitations (reflections, crosstalk), electromagnetic interference (EMI), clock skew, and other problems associated with metallic interconnects will only exacerbate the power dissipation problem and thereby limit the performance of future manycore processors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/free-space_opt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/free-space_opt/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 A Free-space Optical Crossbar Switch Using Wavelength Division Multiplexing and VSCELs   Project Motivation 
This project investigates the application of optical interconnects for use in high-speed massively parallel computer systems. We are currently developing a design for a novel, highly-integrated, highly-scalable optical interconnect architecture call the Scalable Optical Crossbar Network (SOCN).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/hete_arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/hete_arch/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Accelerator-rich Heterogeneous Architectures   Current Researchers: TBD; 
In the dark silicon era, only a fraction of transistors on a chip can be switched simultaneously due to constrained power budget. To improve energy-efficiency, general-purpose cores are augmented with specialized hardware or accelerators. These accelerators, which are optimized for specific applications (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/heterogenous_inter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/heterogenous_inter/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Heterogenous Interconnect Technologies (Photonics, 3D Stacking, RF) for Scalable NoCs   Publications 
R. W. Morris, A. K. Kodi, A. Louri and R. D. Whaley, &amp;ldquo;Three-Dimensional Stacked Nanophotonic Network-on-Chip Architecture with Minimal Reconfiguration,&amp;rdquo; in IEEE Transactions on Computers, vol. 63, no. 1, pp. 243-255, Jan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/machinel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/machinel/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Machine Learning for High Performance, Energy-Efficient and Reliable NoCs   Current Researchers: Ke Wang, Hao Zheng, Jie Luo; 
With continued aggressive technology scaling, Network-on- Chips (NoCs) architectures are facing three major challenges including minimizing power consumption, scaling performance and providing a reliable and robust communication limited by area, power, and cost constraints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/machinel2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/machinel2/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Energy-Efficient Scalable Multicore Architectures   Current Researchers: TBD; 
Over the last decade, Moore’s Law has slowed, while Dennard Scaling has ended. The end of voltage scaling has made power dissipation the fundamental barrier to scaling computing performance across all platforms –from hand-held, embedded systems, to laptops, to servers, to datacenters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/multi-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/multi-domain/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Multi-Domain Modeling and Simulation of Optical Interconnects for Multiprocessor Application   Project Description 
The end-to-end system design and simulation of optical interconnects for high performance and scalable multiprocessor systems for box-to-box, backplane, intra-board and intra-chip applications must address a number of considerations including system performance, power consumption, thermal properties, and cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/multi-wavelength/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/multi-wavelength/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Multi-Wavelength Optical Content Addressable Parallel Processor (MW-OCAPP)   Project Motivation 
Databases are becoming key elements in the Information Age. Database machines, likewise, are the central enablers for current and future progress in Information Technology. Optics, because of its inherent parallelism, has long been seen as a vehicle for large-scale database processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/nano-photo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/nano-photo/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Nano-Photonics for Network on Chips   Publications 
R. Morris, A. K. Kodi and A. Louri, &amp;ldquo;Dynamic Reconfiguration of 3D Photonic Networks-on-Chip for Maximizing Performance and Improving Fault Tolerance,&amp;rdquo; in Proceedings of the 2012 45th Annual IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Microarchitecture, Vancouver, BC, 2012, pp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/neardatacomp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/neardatacomp/</guid>
      <description>Approximate Communication   Recent research has shown that on-chip data movement consumes much more power than computation and this trend will continue in the future. Additionally, some algorithms and applications, such as machine learning, big data analysis, image/video processing and computer vision are tolerant to modest errors. These applications are inherently tolerant to some error in their output whether due to noisy input data, multiple correct answers or not requiring very accurate execution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/nnaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/nnaa/</guid>
      <description>Neural Networks Accelerator and Applications   Neural networks (NNs) have been successfully implemented in modern artificial intelligence (AI) applications ranging from image processing to speech recognition to natural language processing. While NNs deliver superior accuracy, they still suffer from the high cost of computational complexity and a significant amount of data movement. For example, convolutional neural networks (CNNs) are the most representative class of NNs, which have been widely applied to image classification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/optical_interconnects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/optical_interconnects/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Optical Interconnects for the Design of Large Scale Symmetric Multiprocessors   Project Motivation 
Symmetric multiprocessors (SMPs) are attractive parallel computers widely used, since they provide a global physical address space and a symmetric access to the entire memory with increased flexibility and programmability. SMPs use fast snooping protocols to maintain cache coherence by broadcasting every request on the shared bus connecting all modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/optical_multi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/optical_multi/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Optical Multi-Mesh Hypercube Interconnection Network   Project Motivation As both silicon and GaAs based technologies drive device speed into the gigahertz (Ghz) frequency range, and rise times down to small fractions of nanoseconds, communications, not device speed, between subsystems and chips at higher and higher data rates are the limiting and decisive factor for performance and cost of high-speed computing systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/optical_proc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/optical_proc/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Optical Processing Techniques for High Speed Searching and Matching Applications   Project Description 
Searching in its various forms has emerged as a fundamental and decisive operation in many of these applications including database processing, artificial intelligence, data mining, security, high-performance computing, and communications. Searching and table lookup can be significantly improved by the use of the content-addressable memory ( CAM ) processing model instead of the location-addressable memory model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/optical_switching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/optical_switching/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Optical Switching Fabrics for Scalable IP Routers   Project Description 
The increasing dependence of today&#39;s information infrastructure on the Internet is due partly to the robust and flexible IP and advancements in optical fiber communication technology. It has already been observed that the Internet traffic doubles every 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/perf_adapt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/perf_adapt/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Performance-Adaptive and Power-Aware Hybrid Opto-Electronic Interconnects for HPCs   [A] Architecture and Algorithms 
As communication distances and bit rates increase, opto-electronic interconnects are being deployed for designing highbandwidth low-latency interconnection networks for high performance computing (HPC) systems. While bandwidth scaling with efficient multiplexing techniques (wavelengths, time and space) are available, static assignment of wavelengths can be detrimental to network performance for non-uniform (adversial) workloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/reliable_and_fault/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/reliable_and_fault/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Reliable and Fault-Tolerant Network-on-Chips for Multi-Core Architectures and Embedded Systems   Project Description 
This research addresses the reliability and fault tolerance of the Network-on-Chip (NoC) as the number of cores on the chip increases. It balances reliability, power-efficiency and performance. It consists of four inter related projects: (1) Multi-layer fault tolerance spanning from devices to applications (2) Tackling both hard faults and soft errors within a NoC router (3) Tackling only hard faults within a NoC router (4) Tackling only soft errors within a NoC router.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topic</title>
      <link>https://hpcat.github.io/scalable_cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hpcat.github.io/scalable_cache/</guid>
      <description>//p { // text-indent: 50px; // } a { font-weight: 900; text-decoration: underline; } br { line-height: 0.0; }  
 Scalable Cache Coherent Scheme for Distributed Shared Memory Systems   Project Description 
As we slowly approach the physical limits of processor and memory speed, it is becoming more attractive to use multiprocessors to increase computing power. Two kinds of parallel processors have become popular: tightly coupled shared memory multiprocessor and distributed memory multiprocessors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>